M.Abdur Rehman

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with more than 2 years of experience in development. Involved in requirement gathering, and deployment. An enthusiastic team player and a creative thinker. Computer Science fanatic Expert programmer, fast learner, always curious, interested in full-stack software/web development. I'm excited to learn more about artificial intelligence and machine learning.

\times	rehmanalira@outlook.com
•	923470072781
9	Faisalabad, Pakistan
in	linkedin.com/in/rehmanalira

github.com/rehmanalira 🚺

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Al- Nahar Solutions

05/2020 - Present

Faisalabad, Pakistan

Working as web application developer main goal to develop the application according the client requirements and impress the client with our work

Junior Developer Step Up It Solutions

05/2019 - 03/2020

Faisalabad, Pakistan

Starting Internship and after a few months worked as a junior web developer completed the tasks of the software house and created frontend websites

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science

Government College University, Faisalabad

07/2019 - 07/2023

F. SC Pre-Engineering

The Concept College, Khiderwala

08/2017 - 05/2019

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Shopify API Integration with Web application (12/2021 - 06/2022)

 I have to connect the API with the Web Application and have to fetch all the orders and customer detail from the Shopify API and also keep Every Record Order Created in the database. Also updated the detail of Shopify shop i.e creates orders, update orders, update the prices, etc.

Courier Service API Integration (10/2021 - 12/2021)

 I have to place all the orders which have been created through the Shopify API in just one click and they will be automatically shipped to their selected Courier service API like Daewoo FastEx & Call Courier

University Management System (02/2022 - 03/2022)

 In This, we can add teachers, classes, departments, and class time which will be Auto-Assigned to the teachers and we can generate Reports from it. All CRUD operations are done in it and the backend framework I used is Laravel & language is PHP

Pak Wheels Car Data Information Machine Learning Python (05/2022 - 05/2022)

In this project, we get all the latest detailed information about the
cars like their price, model, engine no, etc from the biggest car
website of Pakistan Pak Wheels using the Python programming
language and its library Beautiful Soap and stored all the
information in CSV file. I wrote many machine learning models like
Random Forrest Regressor & Decision Tree Regressor etc

Heart Failure Prediction Machine Learning Python (03/2022 - 03/2022)

 In this, I have to predict the Heart Failure chances of a person according to the information provided to us. This project was made in Python programming language and used libraries like Pandas, NumPy, and matplotlib

Boston House Price Prediction Machine Learning Python (03/2022 - 04/2022)

 In this, I have to predict the price of houses in Boston and provide information is it the house is a loss or a profit. This project was made in Python programming language and used libraries like pandas, NumPy, and matplotlib.